<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Max In Business</title>
    <description>Follow my entrepreneurial journey.
</description>
    <link>http://yourdomain.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://yourdomain.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 22:00:25 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 22:00:25 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thoughts on the Foundation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Idea extraction through “talking to the market” before coming up with any ideas is an essential part of what &lt;a href=&quot;https://thefoundation.com/&quot;&gt;the Foundation&lt;/a&gt; teaches. Luckily they don’t keep their philosophy a secret so joining is not a must in order to make use of their teachings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously a membership would have it’s advantages. It seems to be a lot more than just some “online course”. What woule be the biggest plus for me is the network of talented and highly driven entrepreneurs. But there’re several things putting me off the idea of joining at this point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What bothers me the most is the &lt;strong&gt;agressive marketing&lt;/strong&gt; right from the start. One doesn’t even see the website when visting it first. Instead one gets access to a free course that would otherwise be $997. Just answer a few questions to make it appear more personalized and off you go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “Start Here” page is essentially an endless &lt;strong&gt;sales letter&lt;/strong&gt; full of great points and reasons to apply. Yet &lt;strong&gt;no mention of the admission fee&lt;/strong&gt;. Why keep it a secret? It’s not like it wouldn’t be a web search away anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a business perspective the admission fee, when accepted into the program, isn’t all that bad. So why not just put it right there on the website? Anyone who’s serious will happily pay and see it as an investment. Keeping it a “secret” just adds to the way to the negative impression the overly aggressive marketing leaves behind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently there’s some sort of selection process. So not everyone can join. That’s a good thing as it may help keeing those incompatible with the program out. But if that’s really the case, why market it so aggressively? Sometimes less is more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all I got put off by it pretty quickly. The Foundations philosophy appears valid. Finding out if it works for me is therefore a great investment of time and energy. I look forward to the process and seeing what kind of results it yields. Depending on that I might even consider applying for the program. Until then however, I’ll keep my distance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 21:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/advantages-of-the-experimental-mindset.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/advantages-of-the-experimental-mindset.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Advantages of the experimental mindset</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One problem I ran into quickly when looking into idea extraction is paralysis by analysis. Worried about choosing the right industries I wasted valuable time over stuff I didn’t really find or understand well. In the end I had nothing but even more self doubt. That’s when I decided to care less about success and focus mostly on the process instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Caring deeply about your success is a good thing. But pair that with inexperience and your chances of success become abysmally small. To really succeed a certain level of skill and self confidence is required. That’s why I deliberately chose to do nothing but experimental idea extraction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of worrying about all details, remove unnecessary steps. Don’t worry about getting all your research right. Focus on moving forward and taking action instead. But most of all, don’t expect to end up a millionaire at the end. Set a much simpler goal. Mine is to grow comfortable with the whole process of idea extraction and ultimately end up with one solid idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With nothing on the line I feel it’s easier to relax and accept mistakes. They become harmless learning experiences and won’t be made again once the going gets tougher. It’s a bit like a flight simulator. Try things out, crash the plane as often as you like, go a bit crazy and ultimately learn how to handle the real thing without crashing and burning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 21:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/thoughts-on-the-foundation.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/thoughts-on-the-foundation.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Giving Idea Extraction a try</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Inspired by my recent re-discovery of &lt;a href=&quot;https://thefoundation.com&quot;&gt;the Foundation&lt;/a&gt; by Dane Maxwell I picked myself up to start over. A critical part of the Foundation’s philosophy is the idea extraction process during which one gets to know the unsatisfied needs of a potential customer base. Based on that ideas form, products take shape and value is created for everyone involved – in theory, anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to come up with a vague idea based on some half hearted observation or any other unreliable inspiration. Action taking entrepreneurs go straight to work on it and after a week or two the project is dead. Do this over and over and you’ll feel like the biggest loser in history. Sadly, I write from experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therein lays the attraction of the Foundation’s approach to finding ideas. By the time one comes up with one it’s already verified by the potential customer. No more guessing, no more self doubt, no more vagueness and perhaps even pre-sales funding the project before any concrete action has been taken. One doesn’t have to be a member of the Foundation, which I’m not, to appreciate that concept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Let’s get to work&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to give the whole process a try and worked out an experimental strategy to see if this approach is right for me. If successful at least one solid idea is born.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The all important first step is to find an industry. I quickly stopped digging the web for industry reports, trends, etc. A healthy guess and some key figures (e.g. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ibisworld.com/&quot;&gt;IBISWorld&lt;/a&gt;) will have to suffice for now. Otherwise I’d probably get lost before I even left the ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll also drop the thought of choosing multiple industries. For the sake of this experiment one will do. At this point speedy progress and learning the process is more important than ultimate success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In step two I’ll find all the major corner stones of information regarding the industry. Industry associations, magazines, forums, influential blogs, etc. are the main targets. From that I hope to gain lists of individual businesses in the industry and get to know the whole industry from a high level perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up will be the consolidation of actual contacts. This will be the all important list of people I’ll contact through email and cold-calls. I don’t have an actual strategy on how to do that, yet. It’s probably something I’ll have to learn along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What follows is make or break time. Contacting these total strangers and pick their brains. To me this might be the biggest learning experience during this experiment. Overcoming that intense emotional roller coaster when cold calling other people and finding ways to get what I want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Follow me&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose to make this whole process as transparent as possible. By doing so I hope to provide value to anyone looking into the concept of idea extraction themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To stay tuned, please follow me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mfischer767&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/profile.php?id=100011712550971&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/u/0/106621491299094082108&quot;&gt;Google+&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCCFqEqi43jM8uS0fzKwFzRQ&quot;&gt;Youtube&lt;/a&gt; and subscribe to this blogs &lt;a href=&quot;/feed.xml&quot;&gt;Feed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/giving-idea-extraction-a-try.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/giving-idea-extraction-a-try.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
